We mentioned earlier that when making calculations, it's important to
我们之前提到过在计算时 要重点理解每一字段的
understand the data types in the fields, so you can avoid running into errors.
数据格式 这可以避免出错
Using Alteryx, we'll look at field types in our files and change them so
使用 Alteryx 软件可以查看文件中字段的数据格式 并将字段设置成 00:00:13,448 --&gt; 00:00:15,462 便于计算的数据格式
We're going to start with a file from the Alteryx samples directory called
我们使用 Alteryx 样本目录中的一个文件为例
statepopulatons.csv.
名字为 statepopulatons.csv 的文件
CSV files contain a series of strings separated by commas.
CSV 文件包含一系列由逗号分隔开的字符串
So when opened in Alteryx, each of the fields will be these string field types.
所以在 Alteryx 打开文件时 文件的每个字段都是字符串格式
I'd like to create a new field that is the population density
我想要创建一个新的字段 即每平方英里
per area square mile.
的人口密度
As you can see, we have an Area field, and we have a Total Population field.
正如你所看到的 我们有一个 Area（面积）字段 一个 Total Population（总人口）字段
So to make this calculation,
所以要做这个计算
we're simply going to divide the population by area.
我们只用将总人口数除以总面积
If we try to do this without changing the data types,
如果用字段的原有数据格式来计算
these fields will get an error message.
就会得到一个错误
I'll attach the Formula tool, and create the new field, called Pop Density.
添加 Formula 工具 创建一个新的字段 名字是 Pop Density
Then, to create the formula to calculate the Population Density,
然后 创建计算人口密度的公式
I'll select the population, divide that by area square miles.
我选择用人口总数 除以面积的平方英里数
When I do this, I immediately get an error message,
这样做 会得到一个错误提示
saying formula try to apply numeric operator to string value.
提示使用者试图将值运算符用于字符串格式数据
We can't divide or do arithmetic on string fields.
我们不能除以字符串格式数据 也不能做任何的值运算
We'll need to change the field types from strings to number.
我们需要将字段从字符串类格式化成值格式
To do this I'm to going to introduce two methods using the Select tool and
我将介绍两种方式来实现此转换 Select 工具
the Auto-Field tool.
和 Auto-Field 工具
First, to use the Select tool, we're going to drop it on the line
首先 使用 Select 工具 需要将其放在
in-between the File Input and the Formula tool.
File Input 工具 和 Formula 工具之间
From here, we're going to change the area square miles and
由此 我们将面积的平方公里数和
the total population to numbers.
总的人口数转化成值格式
Because the area square miles has decimal places in it
因为面积的平方公里数里有小数点
we can choose a double for this value, which can handle decimals.
我们可以选择双精度数据格式 可以处理小数点
The Total Population field is a whole number, so
总人口数字段是整数
we'll select int64, which is an integer.
我们可以选择 int64 格式 整数格式
The field types are explained in great detail in the help in Alteryx,
关于字段类型 在 Alteryx 的帮助文档中已经解释的很详细了
which you can bring up by simply hitting F1 on the keyboard,
只需要敲一下键盘上的 F1 就可以看到
while the Select tool is active.
现在 Select 工具被连接上了
Now if we run our workflow, the Formula tool will work.
如果我们运行 workflow 此时的 Formula 工具就可以正常使用了
And a new field with our Population Density will be populated.
计算得出的人口密度就被填充在新字段里了
To bring this new field up, we simply click on the anchor
要看到这个新的字段 只需要点击下 Formula 工具的末端
at the end of the Formula tool and the new field will be shown below.
新的字段将会显示如下
Another way to change field types is an alternative to the Select tool,
另一种改变字段格式的方法是 Select 工具的替代方法
by using the Auto-Field tool.
使用 Auto-Field 工具
If you had too many fields in your file and
如果你的文件中有太多字段
you didn't want to manually change each one, you could use the Auto-Field tool.
你不想每一个字段都自己修改 应使用 Auto-Field 工具
As it can change all of the string fields automatically
它自动将所有的字符串格式字段更改
to the most appropriate field type that fits with its data.
为适合该字段的数据格式
You can find it by searching for Auto-Field in the search bar,
你可以通过 searching for 在搜索栏中找到 Auto-Field 工具
connected to the Input File, and simply run the workflow.
将其添加在 Input File 后 然后运行 workflow
You won't notice anything different in the data, but
在数据中看不到任何的改变 但
if you do click on the Metadata over
如果你点击一下左边的 Metadata
here on the left, you'll notice that the field types and sizes have changed.
你就会发现字段类型和大小变了
So these are the types and sizes for the output.
这些是输出的字段的类型和大小
These are the field types and sizes for the input.
这些是输入的字段的类型和大小
Notice how they all started as vstring254, and
可以看到输入的数据格式都是 vstring254 类型
they became a variety of different sizes and formats.
输出时就变成了各种各样的格式和大小了